# **Supath Dhital**

Lamachaur-16, Pokhara Kaski, 33700, Nepal | +977-9861071618 | supathdh990@gmail.com

## **Summary**

I am Supath Dhital an enthusiastic, self-motivated, punctual, passionate learner and Geospatial Data Science Learner from Nepal having an experience of few GeoAI work. As I have a high interest in GeoAI, Spatial Data Science, and working on several projects related to AI and work with satellite image data analysis and data visualization.

### **Education**

### Pashchimanchal Campus (W.R.C)

Lamachaur-16, Pokhara Nepal

Bachelor of Geomatics Engineering

2018-2023

Relevant Coursework on Earth Science, Geoinformatics, Surveying, Remote Sensing, Cartography, Applications of GIS with Python Several Satellite Image analysis work as well as Cartographic Practices

REHDON College
Computer Science [GPA: 3.71/4]
Samakhusi, Kathmandu
2016-2018

Relevant Coursework on Physics, Chemistry, Mathematics and Computer Science

## **Experience**

**O**mdena

Palo Alto California, USA

Jan 2023 - Present

Junior ML Engineer (Remote)

- Predicting the Nitrogen flow from the farm used as Nitrogen fertilizer to the Nitrous Oxide: One of the top contributors to greenhouse gas using Deep Learning on Remote Sensing data and Validating using Ground truth data following IPCC standard
- Accomplished flood prediction in Belgrade, Serbia using Deep Learning from past meteorological water level data of Danube and Sava river and precipitation data
- Done Dark Corridors mapping for Bats in Brussel, Belgium using Computer Vision and Remote Sensing

#### Humanitarian OpenStreetMap

Washington DC,USA

Data Quality Intern (Remote)

Oct 2022 - Jan 2023

- Done mapping activities of several disaster prone areas as well as digitized geographic features to produce the open 3D geodata which can be used to Governmental bodies or NGOs for post analysis of several natural disasters and so on
- Several Web Maps and thematic Maps practices for Visualizing the Open Geo Data

# **Pashchimanchal Campus**

Lamachaur -16, Pokhara Nepal

Predicting weather patterns in Kaski District

Jun 2022 - Feb 2023

• On behalf of the final year project (thesis) of undergraduate, me along with my team have predict the precipitation and temperature from past meteorological data and satellite netCDF data and compare them

**Drone Data Processing** 

Jan 2023

• Done Drone data abstraction, processing, digitizing of whole Paschimanchal Campus

## **Activities & Extracurriculars**

Participatory Mapping, Trainer/ Mapping and Visualizing thematic maps

Jan 2022 - Feb 2022

• Done Mapping work by training the volunteers using OSM and using extracted geodata preparing the thematic maps to convey the message regarding awareness from disasters other emergency periods

Volunteering, Member

2021-2022

• Accomplished as a member of 7th Executive Committee of Geomatics Engineering Students' Society of Nepal (GESAN): Leading organization to provide training, webinars and so many extra curricular activities related to Earth Data, Geoinformatics

### Certifications

Columental	
Machine Learning and Deep Learning Specialization, Coursera	2023
Image processing and Data Visualization with python, seaborn and Xarray, DataCamp	2022
Spatial Data Science: The New Frontier in Analytics, ESRI	2022
Landslide Risk Modeling using Satellite Imagery, The Geohazards Research Seminar, Medellín Colombia with ITC	2022
Geoinformatics Summer School, State Key Laboratory of Information Engineering in Surveying, Mapping and Remote Sensing	
(LIESMARS) at Wuhan University	2022
Training/Workshop on DGPS and Terrestrial LiDAR Scanner, Center for Space Science and Geomatics Studies (CSSGS)	2022
Application of Geographic Information System(GIS) Application in Hydrology, SuperMap	2021
WebGIS, Geomatics Engineering Students' Society of Nepal (GESAN)	2021

# **Skills & Interests**

Languages: Native- Nepali, Fluent - English, Fluent- Hindi

**Programming, Tools and Environment:** Python, Keras, Tensorflow, pytorch, torchgeo, geopandas, Computer Vision, GDAL, Git, PostGIS, MATLAB, Jupyter Notebook, Matplotlib, Xarray, HTML, CSS, Javascript

Softwares: QGIS, ArcMap, ENVI, Pix4DMapper, SNAP, JOSM, Global Mapper, HEC-RAS, Leica Infinity, HEC-RAS